<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Governance on Ray&#39;s Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://arraysrh.com/tags/governance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Governance on Ray&#39;s Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 11:00:59 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://arraysrh.com/tags/governance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Map: Major Trading Partner</title>
      <link>https://arraysrh.com/tools/tool-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arraysrh.com/tools/tool-1/</guid>
      <description>The following map uses data from the IMF Direction of Trade.
IMF Trade Mapbody {font-family: sans-serif;margin: 20px;}#container {max-width: 800px;margin: auto;}#map {height: 700px;width: 100%;}#slider-container {margin-top: 20px;width: 159%;}input[type=&#34;range&#34;] {width: 100%;}#slider-label {text-align: center;margin-top: 5px;font-size: 1.1em;}let allData = [];let periods = [];fetch(&#39;/data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 7: Visualizing Global Imports from Major Economic Powers (China, EU, USA) since 2000</title>
      <link>https://arraysrh.com/projects/project-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arraysrh.com/projects/project-7/</guid>
      <description>Use IMF API to automatically collect relevant data soures Process data as needed Create metrics to define majority import (in this case which ever of the three countries the share of the imports are from) Combine geojson file with data so that there is a proper geospatial file with the neceesary information Creating visuals of the dataset Start to finish process in one Jupyter Notebook    GitHub Repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 6: Bike Infrastructure Availability &amp; Quality in Berlin vs. Amsterdamm</title>
      <link>https://arraysrh.com/projects/project-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arraysrh.com/projects/project-6/</guid>
      <description>Define metrics:  Availability = Bike Paths (km)/ Roads (km) Quality = ( Seperated Bikepaths / All Bike Paths )*100   Utilize API to collect data from OpenStreetMap Acquire appropriate shapefiles from the city authorities Clean and process data Create data visualizations and report findings    GitHub Repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 5: Predicting Vote &amp; Ideology with Demographics and Browsing Data (Thesis)</title>
      <link>https://arraysrh.com/projects/project-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arraysrh.com/projects/project-5/</guid>
      <description>Extracted features from the Media Exposure and Opinion Formation (MEOF) survey. Processed large quantities (millions of rows) of user trace data from YouGov Utilized Python and R for proper data cleaning Segmented and documented code for modularized implementation Optimized Machine Learning models, neural networks, and utilized natural language processing for topic modeling  The model performance for ideology is significantly better.     GitHub Repository
Paper</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 4: Natural Language Processing 25 Years of EU Climate Policy</title>
      <link>https://arraysrh.com/projects/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arraysrh.com/projects/project-4/</guid>
      <description>This project expands on the work by Sewerin, S., Kaack, L.H., Küttel, J. et al. Towards understanding policy design through text-as-data approaches: The policy design annotations (POLIANNA) dataset. Sci Data 10, 896 (2023). https://doi.org/10.1038/s41597-023-02801-z.
The POLIANNA is a dataset of policy texts from the European Union (EU) that are annotated based on theoretical concepts of policy design, which can be used to develop supervised machine learning approaches for scaling policy analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>