<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Collection on Ray&#39;s Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://rayh-1.github.io/Ray_Portfolio/tags/data-collection/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Collection on Ray&#39;s Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 11:00:59 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rayh-1.github.io/Ray_Portfolio/tags/data-collection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 7: Visualizing Global Imports from Major Economic Powers (China, EU, USA) since 2000</title>
      <link>https://rayh-1.github.io/Ray_Portfolio/projects/project-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rayh-1.github.io/Ray_Portfolio/projects/project-7/</guid>
      <description>Use IMF API to automatically collect relevant data soures Process data as needed Create metrics to define majority import (in this case which ever of the three countries the share of the imports are from) Combine geojson file with data so that there is a proper geospatial file with the neceesary information Creating visuals of the dataset Start to finish process in one Jupyter Notebook    GitHub Repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 6: Bike Infrastructure Availability &amp; Quality in Berlin vs. Amsterdamm</title>
      <link>https://rayh-1.github.io/Ray_Portfolio/projects/project-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rayh-1.github.io/Ray_Portfolio/projects/project-6/</guid>
      <description>Define metrics:  Availability = Bike Paths (km)/ Roads (km) Quality = ( Seperated Bikepaths / All Bike Paths )*100   Utilize API to collect data from OpenStreetMap Acquire appropriate shapefiles from the city authorities Clean and process data Create data visualizations and report findings    GitHub Repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 4: Natural Language Processing 25 Years of EU Climate Policy</title>
      <link>https://rayh-1.github.io/Ray_Portfolio/projects/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rayh-1.github.io/Ray_Portfolio/projects/project-4/</guid>
      <description>This project expands on the work by Sewerin, S., Kaack, L.H., Küttel, J. et al. Towards understanding policy design through text-as-data approaches: The policy design annotations (POLIANNA) dataset. Sci Data 10, 896 (2023). https://doi.org/10.1038/s41597-023-02801-z.
The POLIANNA is a dataset of policy texts from the European Union (EU) that are annotated based on theoretical concepts of policy design, which can be used to develop supervised machine learning approaches for scaling policy analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: Building Geospatial Visualizations with Leaflet</title>
      <link>https://rayh-1.github.io/Ray_Portfolio/projects/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rayh-1.github.io/Ray_Portfolio/projects/project-1/</guid>
      <description>This is a student-run workshop workshop session on the Leaflet package in R.
 equip attendees with conceptual knowledge about the leaflet package and some of its applications for geospatial analysis show attendees key functions and the basic steps to make an interactive map in R provide attendees with practice exercises as well as some further material that can be useful for the topic of this workshop  Tasks involed:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>